Guide to the James H. Bramble papers, 1962-1997.
Bramble, James H. papers, 1962-1997
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
James H. Bramble papers, 1962-1997.
14-19-3308
J. H.(James H.) Bramble
2.4 cubic ft.
Correspondence, lecture, notes.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
The collection contains correspondence, notes, talks, lectures, and papers by J.H.B. and others.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
A. B. Brown University, 1953; M.A. Mathematics, 1955 and Ph.D. Mathematics, 1958, University of Maryland. Professor Bramble is currently a Professor Emeritus at Cornell University and Distinguished Professor of Mathematics at Texas A&M University with a research interest in partial differential equations (PDE), numerical methods for PDE, and multigrid methods.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
The collection contains correspondence, notes, talks, lectures, and papers by J.H.B. and others.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Bramble, J. H.
Subjects:
Mathematics--Study and teaching.; Differential equations, partial--Study and Teaching.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Efficient higher order multistep methods for nonlinear parabolic equations, J. H. B. and Peter H. Sammon; Efficient higher order single step methods for parabolic problems: part II, J. H. B. and P. H. S., 1983 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Multi-step paper, Sammon, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Single and multi-step papers, mss. copies,Bramble and Sammon, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- An efficient numerical procedure for the computation of steady state harmonic currents in flat plates, Joseph E. Pasciak, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- J. B. talks and notes on research, 1971-1973, 19-- (Box 1, Folder 5)
- J. B. talks and notes on research, 1976-1979, 19-- (Box 1, Folder 6)
- U. Tenn. April '81 I, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 7-8)
- Talk on eddy currents, U. of Delaware, fall '83, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- K operator, with J. Schatz, 19-- (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Parametrization methods, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Interface alpha domain, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Integro differential equations, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Simply supported plate, J. H. B. and Richard S. Falk, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Plates problems, J. H. B. and R. S. Falk, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Biharmonic solver, Ciarlet-Raviart, 19-- (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Advanced numerical analysis course materials, 19-- (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Multilevel preconditioner, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Difference approximately 2 pt. b.v.p. Non-uniform mesh, h2 - piecewise C2, 19-- (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Minor results, 19-- (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Symmetric g. s., 19-- (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Difference methods for the generalized Dirichlet problem, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- On the convergence of differenc approximation to weak solutions in Dirichlet's problem, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- SIAM lectures, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Institute seminar, Bramble and Hubbard, Fall, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Approximation methods in elliptic equations, lectures by Bramble and Payne, 19-- (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Lectures Toronto, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Parabolic problems, 1976, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Preconditioning for mixed methods, talk at Babuska conf., 1986 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Multigrid talk, IMACS, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Interpolation lecture, 19-- (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Lecture notes Spring, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- JOE, 19-- (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Lecture notes, 19-- (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Course notes, Math 627, part II, Math 628, 19-- (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Math 627, Fall, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Math 627, Fall - Iterative methods, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Lecture notes for Math 627 Spring 1988: Multigrid - Multilevel (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Math 627, Spring, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Math 627, Spring, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 7-8)
- Notes about lectures Math 627, 19-- (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Math 296 notes, 19-- (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Math 423, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Math 521, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Math 112, 1967-1971, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 13-20)
- Math 111-112, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Applied Math, 1979-1985 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Stokes papers, 1971-1984 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Milner-Rairo, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Trangenstein, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Fairweather, 1984-1985 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Referee's reports, 1980-1983 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Numerical Functional Analysis and Optimization (Nashed), 1985 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Proposal reviews, 1984-1987 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Bramble-Pasciak-Schatz proposal, 1980-1984 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Stokes - Elasticity, 1980-1988 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Jum Douglas meeting, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- N. S. Adj. Multigrid with J. P. and J. X., 19-- (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Multigrid, 1983-1985 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Riaro paper submitted, 1985-1986 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- SIAM (Society for Industrial and Applied Mathematics), 1987 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Axelsson - PCG special issue (BIT) due 10/15/1988 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Xu, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Eddy current - Ping Lee, 19-- (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Tom King, 1987-1988 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Rutgers, November, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Proskurowski - Domain decomposition issue, Applied Numerical Mathermatics, 1987-1988 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Mark Hanisch, 1980-1989 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Search for director Center for Applied Mathematics, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 23)